AARON VONTELL

860-805-0050
vontell@mit.edu
github.com/vontell
avontell.com
LinkedIn: goo.gl/2tpxbh

229 Vassar Street Cambridge, MA 02139

Profile

I am a junior at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, pursuing a dual degree in Computer Science and Mathematics. I have five years of full stack software development experience. I have completed three years of a software development internship, worked on many personal side projects, and worked with / started multiple startups.

Work Experience

Battlecode Competition, MIT - 2016 - Present

I am one of about ten developers who manage, create, and code the inner workings of Battlecode, MITs most popular coding competition with thousands of players and \$50,000+ of prizes. Played as a contestant in 2015, and recruited as a developer of the game in 2016. Duties include creating the yearly game in Java, managing / developing websites, and using creativity to plan the yearly game. See more at http://www.battlecode.org/

Contractual Android Work, Sysdyne Corp; Stamford, CT — Winter 2016 Worked as a contractor to create an Android Application for the delivery and management of concrete, called iSTRADA. Tasks included creating an appealing mobile front end, as well connecting to a RESTful backend written in Node. Also included the challenge of working with developers in different areas of the world.

Android Application Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2014 Duties included developing proof-of-concept software and Android applications using the Java programming language, in conjunction with external libraries and devices. Multiple projects were completed in accordance to a schedule, and collaboration and teamwork were used throughout each project.

Web Application Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2015

Duties included creating web applications using next generation web technologies (HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS) for integration into a larger web application. Work also included writing many PL/SQL stored procedures and writing scripts in Python to give websites offline capabilities.

Full Stack Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2016

Duties included all tasks as discussed above, in addition to building servers and REST backends using the Spring Framework in Java. Also included exposure to Linux-based systems and development tools.

Lead Software Developer, Parcio; Boston, MA — 2014 - 2015

Duties include developing an Android and iOS application with the startup Parcio. The application includes work with Google APIs, MapQuest Open APIs, Android SDK, iOS development, and a custom REST API. Also requires multiple meetings with city officials and the Department of Transportation. See more at parcio.com

Chief Technology Officer, UpStudent; Cambridge, MA — 2014 - Present Duties include guiding and tutoring students through the college application process, through a detailed lesson plan, simulated interviews, and post-acceptance meetings. Also includes all development of our company's website using Bootstrap and hosting through Github. See more at myupstudent.com

Notable Projects / Code

EasyAPI - Java, 2015 - Present

A Java-based library that parses RESTful APIs into useful objects. EasyAPI hopes to create easy RESTful API interaction by creating a simple object from your API key, and then allowing full API interaction through that object. https://github.com/vontell/EasyAPI

EngLang - Python, Lisp, 2016 - Present

EngLang is a syntax-lenient yet deterministic programming language that takes human text and parses it into executable code. Utilizes natural language processing, machine learning, and artificial intelligence to parse the human input. Currently in early stages of development. https://github.com/EngLang

IndicatorBinder - Android Library, 2016 - Present

IndicatorBinder is a library that provides the ability to attach indicators to ViewPagers, so that the user may see their current position within the ViewPager. Aims to provide minimal setup and dependencies for creating these indicators. https://github.com/vontell/IndicatorBinder

Expressivo - Test/Spec Example, Software Class Spring 2016

Homework assignment from 6.005 (Spring 2016) for evaluating and simplifying expressions. Shared here as an example of full coverage test suites and highly documented code. *Available at https://github.com/vontell/Expressivo* as a private repo (for access, email me at vontell@mit.edu)

Education

40+ college credits from University of Hartford during high school, 2011 - 2014

Currently enrolled in Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2014 - present

Pursuing Computer Science Major and Mathematics Major, with a focus on Quantum Computing, Concentration in Science, Technology, and Society

Technical Skills

Java Programming (5+ years)

Android Programming (Including multiple APIs) (3 years)

Extensive Git experience (4 years)

Python (3 years)

Full Stack Web Development (HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Angular Material, Spring Framework, minimal Node.js)

Experience with consuming RESTful services (Weather Underground, Google Maps, MapQuest, and more) See EasyAPI above

Some experience with PL/SQL, Objective-C, and Swift

Project Management - Managed several teams and projects both at home and during internships

Photoshop CS6

Autodesk Inventor Professional

Soft Skills

Extensive Experience with the Agile Development Process

Experience working in a large corporation (35,000+ employees)

Worked in development groups of 3-5 developers and 15-20 developers

Actually enjoys writing documentation and commenting code

Passions

Open source software

Following best practices, everywhere and always

Hackathons and coding for good (HackMIT)

Academia, Mathematic, and Quantum Computing (which I plan to pursue professionally)